<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Posts on Njord tech blog</title><link>https://Njorda.github.io/post/</link><description>Recent content in Posts on Njord tech blog</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Mon, 06 Feb 2023 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://Njorda.github.io/post/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Shinylive app with hugo</title><link>https://Njorda.github.io/2023/02/06/hugo-with-python-rshiny/</link><pubDate>Mon, 06 Feb 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://Njorda.github.io/2023/02/06/hugo-with-python-rshiny/</guid><description>Shinylive app with hugo This blog post is based upon RamiKrispin / shinylive where we will take a look in to using Shiny with python and leveraging WebAssembly to let it run in the browser with out a backend. This allows for interactive static webpages.
&amp;lt;iframe src=&amp;quot;https://nikenano.github.io/shinylive/&amp;quot;&amp;gt;&amp;lt;/iframe&amp;gt;</description></item><item><title>Trition with post and pre processing</title><link>https://Njorda.github.io/2023/02/01/Trition_with_post_and_pre_processing/</link><pubDate>Wed, 01 Feb 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://Njorda.github.io/2023/02/01/Trition_with_post_and_pre_processing/</guid><description>Trition with post and pre processing. This is based upon this repo
In this blog post we will dig down in to how a Machine Learning(ML) model can be combined with pre and post processing steps using Nvidia triton. By combining the pre- and post processing the user can make a single call using GPRC or http. It should be noted that we in reality will not merge these processing steps in any way but link the calls together using Tritons ensemble functionality Triton support multiple different backends(processing functionality) and in this case we will use the tensorRT backend for the model serving and the python backend to add the pre and post processing business logic.</description></item><item><title>Trition with post and pre processing</title><link>https://Njorda.github.io/2023/02/01/Trition_with_post_and_pre_processing/</link><pubDate>Wed, 01 Feb 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://Njorda.github.io/2023/02/01/Trition_with_post_and_pre_processing/</guid><description>Prompt engineering With the rise of GPT-3 and Stable diffusion the concpet of promt engineering has gain more and more traction. According to wikipedia the task can be described as
Prompt engineering typically works by converting one or more tasks to a prompt-based dataset and training a language model with what has been called &amp;ldquo;prompt-based learning&amp;rdquo; or just &amp;ldquo;prompt learning&amp;rdquo;
Wikipedia Prompts are inputs for models that expect text as input however the output can very most famously images or text.</description></item><item><title>Welcome to the Blog</title><link>https://Njorda.github.io/2022/07/17/hello-world/</link><pubDate>Sun, 17 Jul 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://Njorda.github.io/2022/07/17/hello-world/</guid><description> “Yeah It&amp;rsquo;s on. ”
Hello World!</description></item></channel></rss>